《鐵面無私》
1930年 禁酒令使芝加哥爆發戰爭
幫派人物爭奪地盤
以走私酒而 掌控億萬元的強大帝國
相互使用暴力手段 來鞏固自己的勢力
這是一個幫派爭鬥的時代 這是梟雄艾爾卡彭的時代
報紙上有篇文章曾這樣報導 事實上你是實際的
An article, which I believe appeared in a newspaper, asked why, since it would seem that you are
芝加哥市長 你只是差一紙委任令而已
in effect the Mayor of Chicago, you're not simply being appointed to that position.
我告訴你，這很動人
Well, I tell ya, it's touching.
人生很多事亦是如此
Like a lot of things in life,
有很多事可笑 因為那是真的
we laugh because it's funny, and we laugh because it's true.
有些人說，改革者也說
Some people say, reformers here say:
「把那人關進監獄，他以為 他在幹什麼？」
"Put that man in jail, what does he think he is doing?"
同樣的，我在幹什麼 你們報紙要弄清楚
What I hope I'm doing, and here's where your paper's got a point,
我是在反映人們的意見
is I'm responding to the will of the people.
人們要喝酒，你知道我知道 大家都知道
People are gonna drink. We all know that.
我只是採取行動
All I do is act on that.
說什麼販賣私酒？ 什麼叫是販賣私酒？
And all this talk of bootlegging. What is bootlegging?
放在船上那叫販賣私酒 放在大酒店那叫盛情好客
On the boat it's bootlegging, on Lake Shore Drive it's hospitality.
我只是個生意人
I'm a businessman.
你怎麼解釋外頭傳聞 你以暴力掌控生意？
Your reputation is that you control your business through violence.
把你的貨強迫推銷出去？
That those that don't purchase your product are dealt with violently.
沒事
It's all right.
我在惡劣環境下長大
I grew up in a tough neighbourhood.
我們常說，「槍桿和好話並用 勝過單單講好話」
We used to say, "Y ou can get further with a kind word and a gun" "than you can with just a kind word."
在我那種環境是真的
And in that neighbourhood it might've been true.
然後你會贏得好名聲
And sometimes your reputation follows you.
芝加哥的確有暴力存在
There is violence in Chicago,
但並不在於我 或是我僱傭的人
but not by me and not by anybody I employ.
我告訴你們原因 因為那不是好生意
Because it's not good business.
（開場）
走開，不要打攪我們 沒事
Leave us alone down here,
我們不需要任何東西
we've got everything we need.
你那些綠色啤酒毫無用處
The green beer you're peddlin' ain't any good.
毫無用處，但很值得一買
It's not supposed to be good. It's supposed to be bought.
我什麼也不買
I'm not buyin' any.
別擔心 我們不會回來了
Don't worry about it, Pops, we won't come back.
你家裏人都好嗎？ 他們很好
- How's everyone at your house today? - They're fine.
你媽媽好嗎？ 她有點感冒
- Is your Mama well? - She has a little cold.
哦，是嗎？
Oh, she does?
我很難過聽到這事 不過，她很快會沒事的
- I'm sorry to hear that. - But she'll be all right.
給你 謝謝
- There you go. - Thank you.
不客氣，小可愛 過馬路時要當心
That's all right, sweetie. You be careful crossin' the street.
先生！先生 告訴你媽媽…
- Mister! - You tell your Mama that...
喂，先生，等一下
Hey, Mister! Wait!
先生，等一下，你忘了你的手提箱…
Mister! Wait! You forgot your brief...
（1930年9月14日星期天）
（1930年9月15日星期一）
（私酒戰爭屠殺十歲女孩）
是的，我聽到收音機廣播了
Yes, I heard it on the radio.
我瞭解
I know.
上班時間到了
Now it's time to go to work.
你要給人第一眼好印象
You'll make a good first impression.
我愛你，艾略特
I love you, Eliot.
走吧
Now, shoo.
艾略特奈斯，財政部特別員
Eliot Ness, Special Agent of the Treasury Department.
奈斯先生 謝謝你，局長
- Mr Ness. - Thank you, Chief.
應芝加哥市民要求
At the request of the City of Chicago,
聯邦政府 令財政部
the Department of the Treasury has inaugurated a programme
成立專案 制止私酒販責 及其所引發的暴力
to deal with the flow of illegal liquor and the violence it creates.
奈斯先生！ 這個計劃包括什麼？
Mr Ness! Of what does this programme consist?
我和其他財政部專員 將與芝加哥警方合作…
I and other agents of the Treasury will be working with the Chicago Police...
這是否又是官僚炒新聞？
Isn't it just another showpiece programme?
你對禁酒令有何看法？ 你喝酒嗎，奈斯先生？
- What do you think of prohibition? - Do you drink, Mr Ness?
奈斯先生，回答問題
- Come on, answer the questions.
這不是炒新聞
- It's not just a showpiece.
我來告訴你們我對禁酒令的看法
And I'll tell you how I feel about prohibition.
那是國家法律
It is the law of the land.
你自認為是掃蕩戰士嗎？ 奈斯先生？
Do you consider yourself a crusader, is that it?
你有何專長可以擔當這個任務？ 你可有政治野心？
What qualifications do you have for the job? Do you have any political ambitions?
好了，今天到此為止
All right, boys, I think that's enough.
最後一個問題，奈斯先生 麻煩讓一下
The last qustion, Mr Ness! Please.
先生，你有何計劃？ 打算如何著手？
What are your real plans? What have you got coming up?
你去看報紙吧
You'll have to read about it in the paper.
讓我和你同去 不
- Let me ride along with you. - No.
我們會配合你的 不，愛莫能助
Can't help you.
奈斯先生，奧德森中尉，飛騎警隊
Mr Ness, Lieutenant Alderson, the Flying Squad.
你準備會見弟兄了嗎？
Are you ready to meet the men?
是的，我準備好了
Yes, I am.
（武器登記預備室）
我還有一件事情要說
I have one more thing to say.
我知道你們很多人喝酒
I know that many of you take a drink.
今天以前的事我不管
What you've done before today is not my concern.
但今後要自律，停止喝酒
But now we must be pure, and I want you to stop.
問題不在於喝酒是否傷身 雖然很可能傷身
It's not a question of whether it's 'a harmless drink'. It may well be.
而在於那違反法律，各位
But it's against the law.
我們要厲行法律便要以身作則
And as we are going to enforce the law, we must do first by example.
有問題嗎？
Are there any questions?
很好
Good.
財政部有位密探臥底一段時間了
The Department of the Treasury's had a man undercover here for some time now.
我們接獲情報
We've received word from this informant
昨天自加拿大運來了大批私酒
that a large shipment of Canadian whiskey has arrived in Chicago.
所以我希望你們準備一下
So I hope that you have signed on for some action.
我們要去抓他們了
We're got for him
記住 私酒箱上有紅色楓葉記號
Remember, the liquor cases are marked with the red maple leaf.
是，長官，我知道
Yes sir
密探穿的是灰大衣白圍巾
The Treasury Agent is in a grey suit with a white scarf.
不要抓他 灰大衣和白圍巾
- He is not to be arrested. - A grey suit and a white scarf.
就這樣，你的人準備好了？ 是的，長官，都準備好了
- That's it. Are your men ready? - Yes, sir. They are.
很好
Good
稍息 準備對付壞蛋
- At ease. - Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
準備如何？ 好了！
- How are we doin' - Okay.
來點三明治？ 不，謝謝長官
- Want part of a sandwich? - No, thank you, sir.
你緊張嗎？ 不，長官
- You nervous? - No, sir.
你在這警局很久了？ 才一陣子
- Been with the unit long? - A short while.
我想大家都想把事做好 是的，長官
- I suppose we all want to do well. - Yes, sir.
（我非常以你為榮！）
我太太寫的字條
A message from my wife.
你結婚了？ 是的
- You married? - Yes, sir, I am.
結婚不錯，是吧？
Nice to be married, huh?
跟我來
Just follow me.
哦，天啊！ 聯邦官員，手舉起來！
- Oh, God... - Federal officer. Hands in the air.
手舉起來，東西放下
Get 'em up. Drop it.
我不能，會砸壞
Damn it, I can't , it'll break.
奈斯，聽著，我正要…
Mr Ness. Look, I was just...
天啊，對不起
Geez, I'm sorry.
聽著，我可以為你做 許多你奮力拚搏的事情
Listen, I can do a lot for you, what you're tryin' to do.
我搶頭條新聞 替你宣揚
I get the big scoop, you make a big splash.
爭取新聞界支持如何
Get some support. What do you say?
讓我幫你，如何？
Let's be real, let me help you.
閉嘴
Okay. Just shut up.
好了，各位… 我們大幹一場吧！
All right now... Let's do some good!
站住別動！
Hold it right there!
聯邦官員！
Federal officer.
你們因違反禁酒令被捕了
You're under arrest for violations of the Volstead Act.
守住門口！ 別讓罪犯逃了！
Let's cover the doors! Don't let anybody out!
普勒斯基
Preseuski.
不好意思，我有許可 誰批准的？
- I'm here with permission. - Who gave you permission?
奈斯先生！ 不要緊，讓他進來
- Mr Ness! - Sorry, let him through here.
讓他進來
Let him through here.
你要拍照就現在拍吧
You want to take your picture, take it now.
準備好了？ 準備好了
- You ready? - Ready.
這是酒？
Liquor, huh?
下雨了嗎？
Rain?
帶他出去 快點
Get him out of here.
把這地方徹底解散！ 現在，帶他出去！
- Tear the place apart! - I mean now, get him out!
是，長官！
Yes sir.
好了，走吧
Ok,let's go.
你也出去
That means you, too.
天啊！
Christ!
（緝酒戰士奈斯灰頭土臉）
（差勁的艾略特奈斯）
（我非常以你為榮！）
你在幹什麼？
Now, what do you think you're doing?
要丟垃圾？ 就丟到垃圾筒裏
You want to throw garbage? Throw it in the goddamn trash basket.
你沒有更重要的事做嗎？
Don't you have more important things to do?
有
Yeah.
但我不必現在去做
But I'm not doing them right now.
我們彼此心知肚明
Do we understand each other?
好了，朋友，別亂動
Okay, pal, why the Mohaska?
你為何帶著槍？ 我是財政部特派員
- Why are you packin' the gun? - I'm a Treasury Officer.
好吧
All right.
你只要記著我們照過面就夠了
Just remember what we talked about now.
喂，等一下！
Hey... Wait a minute!
這個城市的警員是怎麼回事 他們是怎麼教你的？
What the hell kind of police do you have in this goddamn city?
你竟不管帶槍的人
You just turned your back on an armed man.
你是位財政部官員
- You're a Treasury officer.
何以見得？ 那只是我說的而已
- I just told you I was.
誰願意冒充財政部官員？ 我哪管得著？
Who would claim to be that, who was not?
你的姓名和單位？
What's your name and unit?
在這上面
It's right here.
你有牢騷？怎麼回事？
You got a beef? What is it?
你怎麼知道我有帶槍？
How did you know I had a gun?
你要什麼？ 討教會警員的絕招嗎？
What do you want, a free lesson in police work?
不
No.
你還好吧？朋友
Are you okay, pal?
我工作不順利
I had a rough day on the job.
你要回家了嗎？ 我正要回去
- Are you going home now? - I was about to.
你已做到了 執法者規則第一條
Well, then, you just fulfilled the first rule of law enforcement.
確保能活著下班回家
Make sure when your shift is over you go home alive.
第一課結束
Here endeth the lesson.
總數十萬元，一共40桶
$100,000 for 40 barrels.
確保沒有空的
Make sure there are no empties.
我給你的底帳都在帳薄裏
I'm gonna give you the ledger, everything is in the book.
桶是55加侖
55 gallons to the barrel.
我是艾迪 進來，艾迪
- It's Eddie. - Come in, Eddie.
他坐進除雪車裏說道 「我們好好幹一場」
So, he gets into the snowplough, and he says, "Let's do some good" .
然後我們破門而入...
And then, we bust through...
（艾略特奈斯）
（財政部特別調查處）
奈斯先生？ 什麼事？
- Mr Ness? - Yes?
我是來謝謝你的！
I came here to thank you.
被炸死的小女孩是我女兒
It was... ..my little girl that got killed with that bomb.
我很難過，請進
I'm sorry. Please.
我很難過
I'm ...l'm so sorry.
你瞭解…
You see, it's ...
我知道你也有小孩
because I know that you have children, too.
這是那些人帶來的真實悲劇
And that this is real for you, that these men cause us tragedy.
我知道你要阻止他們
And I know that you will put a stop to them.
我知道你會的
And you do that, now.
（拉辛大街）
你要幹什麼？ 我想和你談談
- What do you want? - I'd like to talk to you.
進來吧
Come in.
我要找一批人 奈斯…
I need a small group of men, handpicked, starting with you.
首先指名道姓找上你 奈斯，我只是個可憐的巡夜警員
Ness! I am just a poor beat cop.
我該怎麼幫你？
- Now, how can I help you?
只要和我一起辦事
- Just work with me.
我為什麼要？ 因為你是好警員
- But why should I, though? - Because you're a good cop.
你怎麼知道？ 你告訴我的
- How do you know that? - You told me.
我若是好警員 我還會在這年紀擔任巡夜嗎？
If I'm such a good cop... How come I'm walkin' the beat, then, at my age?
你想告訴我嗎？
Do you want to tell me?
也許是我心地善良
Well, maybe I'm that Whore with a Heart of Gold.
罪惡圈裏唯一的好警員？ 你想聽這些嗎？
Or The One Good Cop in the Bad Town? Is that what you want to hear?
我沒要求你，我不在乎！
I didn't ask you, and I don't care!
你要去巡夜就請便
You want to stay on the beat? You do that.
你願跟我一起嗎？ 我需要你的協助
If you'd like to come with me, I need your help.
我在請你幫忙
I'm askin' you for help.
你在害怕什麼？
Well...that's the thing you fear, isn't it?
奈斯先生，希望我在十年前 還有發福二十磅前就遇到你
Mr Ness, I wish I'd met you ten years and...twenty pounds ago.
但是，我覺得…
But...I just think it got...
對我較重要的便是保住老命
more important to me...to stay alive.
所以我甘心擔任巡夜
And that's why I'm walkin' the beat.
謝謝，我不幹
Thank you, no.
很好，安迪
That's good, Andy.
開車吧，我們去兜風
Let's start up the thing and take a little ride.
我要聽一下 熊貓牌引擎的聲音！
I wanna hear that Stutz Bearcat engine, boy!
好，讓我開車門 好的
- Yeah, let me open the door here. - Yeah, go ahead.
你快去把門撿起來，安迪
Whoopsy daisy, pick up the door there, Andy.
把它扔到後座讓我發動引擎
Throw it in the back seat. Now, let me get the thing started.
對，發動引擎吧
Yeah, start it up, Andy.
天啊！聽聽引擎聲！
Holy mackerel, Andy! Listen to that Bearcat motor!
是啊，聽起來就像大熊 不停追著小貓！
Yeah, it sounds like the bear is chasin' that cat all round it!
安迪，引擎過熱冒煙了！
Andy! She's boilin' over!
奈斯先生？ 什麼事
- Mr Ness? - Yes.
奧斯卡華萊士
Oscar Wallace.
華盛頓派我來的
I've been assigned here by the Washington Bureau.
真的？ 是的
- Really? - Yes.
我非常高興你加入 華萊士先生…對不起？
Well, I'm glad to have you here, Mr Wallace. Would you excuse me?
我們現在一籌莫展 你有建議嗎…
We are a little in the dark here, but any ideas you may have...
是的，我有
Well, actually, yes, sir, I do.
我首先要試的便是這個
And the one I want to try first... is this.
他自1926年就沒有申報過
He has not filed a return since 1926.
申報？ 申報所得稅
- A return...? - An income tax return.
申報所得稅 是的，先生
- Income tax. - Yes, sir.
你在局裏是做什麼的 華萊士？
- What do you do at the Bureau?
我是會計
- Oh, I'm an accountant.
會計？ 是的，總局裏派我來此…
- An accountant? - Yes, and the Bureau sent me here...
失陪了一下？
Would you excuse me?
坐吧
Please.
好了，我們走
Okay. Let's go.
去哪裏？ 這裏隔牆有耳
- Where are we going? - These walls have ears.
你說你想知道 如何扳倒卡彭
You said you wanted to know how to get Capone.
你真的要捉他？
Do you really want to get him? You see what I'm saying?
你明白我的意思？ 你打算怎麼做？
- What are you prepared to do? - Everything within the law.
合法的行動 若不成，你又有何打算？
And then what are you prepared to do?
奈斯先生 如果你打算向他們開戰
If you open the ball on these people,
你就要一直戰鬥下去
you must be prepared to go all the way.
因為他們非和你拚個 你死我活不可
Because they won't give up the fight until one of you is dead.
我想捉卡彭 我不知該如何下手
I want to get Capone. I don't know how.
要捉卡彭，就要比他強
Here's how you get Capone:
他拔刀，你就拔搶
he pulls a knife, you pull a gun.
他傷了你的部下 你就宰了他的爪牙！
He sends one of yours to hospital, you send one of his to the morgue!
那就是芝加哥的規則！ 那就是捉卡彭的方法！
That's the Chicago way! And that's how you get Capone.
你能那樣幹嗎？
Now, do you want to do that?
你準備好那樣干了嗎？
Are you ready to do that?
我提供你這個建議 你要不要接受？
I'm making you a deal. Do you want this deal?
我已發誓要將他繩之以法！
I have sworn to put this man away,
以合法手段 盡我所能去達成
with any and all legal means at my disposal, and I will do so.
天主憎惡懦夫
Well, the Lord hates a coward.
你可瞭解血誓之意義，奈斯先生？
Do you know what a blood oath is, Mr Ness?
是的 很好，你剛剛才發了一個血誓
- Yes. - Good. 'Cause you just took one.
你明白那晚的突襲 何以不成功？
How do you think Capone knew about your raid the other night?
有人通風報信 對，你開竅了
- Somebody on the cops told him. - Right. Welcome to Chicago.
芝加哥就像娼館一樣污穢
This town stinks like a whorehouse at low tide.
首先，你能相信誰？不能 相信任何人，連警察都不行
First, who can you trust? Nobody. The cops, nobody.
這裏沒有人喜歡你 那你為何肯幫我？
- 'Cause nobody wants you here. - Then why are you helping me?
因為我曾宣誓維護法律執行
Because I swore to uphold the law.
你要相信的話 我再告訴你另一件事
And if you believe that, I'll tell you another.
你能信任誰？
- Now, who can you trust?
我誰也不信任 那是件悲哀的事
- I can trust nobody.
我們誰也不能信任的話 要如何取得幫助？
- That's the sorry truth. - Then, where are we gonna get help?
如果你不想拿到爛蘋果 那就別拿桶子裏的
If you're afraid of getting a rotten apple, don't go to the barrel.
去摘樹上的
Get it off the tree.
去樹上摘…
Get it off the tree...
手放在扳機罩 彈出彈夾！
Finger out of the trigger guard! Eject those cartridges!
放下左輪，退後一步！
Lay the revolver on the ledge and stand back!
向後轉！
About face!
賴特，見過艾略特奈斯
Barry! I want you to meet Mr Eliot Ness.
好的 財政部特派員，你好
Treasury Department. How are you?
我們需要人手
We need a recruit for extended duty.
他被借調到財政部
He is to be seconded to the Treasury Department.
我們有財政部的公文 要求協助…
We have the full...
巴裏，這班上誰的射擊 成績最好？
Barry? Who is consistently the best shot of this class?
威廉森和史東 好
- Williamson and Stone.
替我叫他們來好嗎？ 一次一位
- Call them out, one at a time.
抱歉請問他們是否結婚了？
- Are either of the men married? - No.
沒有 很好
- Good.
威廉森！前面和中間 你結過婚了
- Williamson!- You're married.
我不要結過婚的人
- I don't want any married men.
好了，稍息，小伙子 我有些話問你
All right, stand easy, son. I want to ask you something.
你為投考警校？
- Why do you want to join the force?
為了保護… 恩？
- To protect and...
為保護和服務… 保護…
To protect and serve... To protect and...
別背書上的答案
Please don't search for the yearbook answer.
說說你是怎麼想的
Just tell me what you think.
我怎麼想的？我… 你…
- What I think? I... - You...
…以力量去協助別人 我明白了
...could help...the force.
你可以以力量去協助別人
- You can help...
對抗罪犯 謝謝
- With the force. Thank you.
又一位警察局長
There goes the next Chief of Police.
稍息！
At ease!
史東！到這兒來
Stone! Out here.
這小子是個天才
This kid's a prodigy.
（警員學院）
為什麼你想要參加成為警員？
- Why do you want to join the force?
為了保護財產和…
- To protect the property and...
噢，拜託不要跟我說那些廢話
Oh, please, don't waste my time with that bullshit.
史東，你老家在哪？
Where are you from, Stone?
南方 史東？
- From the Southside. - Stone?
喬治史東，你的本名？
George Stone, that's your name?
你的真名？ 這就是我的真名
- What's your real name? - That is my real name.
不！你改名前的名字？
Nah! What was it before you changed it?
吉塞普派特 呀，我早該知道的！
- Giuseppe Petri. - Geez, I knew it!
這就是你所要的 一個盜竊團伙的一員！
That's all you need, one thieving wop on the team!
你說什麼？
What's that you said?
你是一個血統不純的 說謊集團成員
I said that you're a lyin' member of a no-good race.
總比你好 你個臭愛爾蘭豬
That's much better than you, you stinkin' Irish pig.
噢，我喜歡他
Oh, I like him.
是啊，我也喜歡他
Yeah, I like him, too.
孩子，你剛剛加入財政部
You just joined the Treasury Department, son.
行，好啊
Yeah, okay.
艾略特奈斯
Eliot Ness.
來自Stakeouts北方 和西部的報導以及…
With reports from stake-outs on the North and West side, and...
謝謝你，中尉，謝謝
Thank you, Lieutenant. Thank you.
你覺得怎樣？
What do you think?
我覺得這一點都不像雜耍小技
I think there's nothing like vaudeville.
我有同感 喂，你準備好去工作了沒？
- That's what I think. - Now, are you ready to go to work?
去哪兒？ 緝私酒
- Where are we going? - On a liquor raid.
我們得找幫手
We need another man.
奈斯先生？ 這可有意思了
Mr Ness? This is very interesting.
我發現了一個財務支出方式 顯示了…
I've found a financial disbursement pattern which shows some irregu...
你戴著徽章？ 是啊
- You carry a badge? - Yes.
帶一把槍
Carry a gun.
吉姆？ 什麼？
- Jimmy...? - What?
你穿的那算什麼？ 萬聖節？
What the hell are you dressed for? Hallowe'en?
閉嘴，我在工作 哪兒？馬戲團嗎？
Shut up. I'm working. Where? The circus?
（美國郵局）
嗯，我們到了 我們到這裏做什麼？
- Well, here we are. - What are we doing here?
追緝私酒
Liquor raid.
這裏？
Here?!
奈斯先生 人人都知道去哪兒買醉
Everybody knows where the booze is.
問題不是我們找不到酒
The problem isn't finding it.
問題是怎麼找到卡邦
The problem is who wants to cross Capone.
走吧
Let's go.
你最好非常篤定，馬龍
You'd better be damn sure, Malone.
（樓梯間關閉 繞道通行）
如果你現在踏進這個門 你就是走進大麻煩
If you walk through this door, you're walking into a world of trouble.
而且沒有回頭路 懂嗎？
There's no turning back. Do you understand?
是的，我明白
Yes, I do.
好的 把那個斧頭給我
Good. Give me that axe.
聯邦警員！ 舉起手來！
- Federal officers! - Get your hands in the air!
不許動！ 突襲查緝！
- Nobody moves! - This is a raid!
每個人… 你們在這兒幹嘛？
- Everybody... - What are you doin' here?
這裏的一切都被扣押了！ 你們都被捕了！
All this stuff is impounded! You're all under arrest!
嘿！這可不對！喂！ 這樣可不好！
Hey! This isn't right! Hey! This is no good!
你們可有逮捕證？ 當然！這是我的逮捕證
- You got a warrant? - Sure! Here's my warrant.
你覺得他現在會怎麼想？ 好還是壞？
How do you think he feels now? Better...or worse?
那是什麼？ 什麼那是什麼？
- What is that? - What is that?
是的，什麼什麼？ 上帝，這天兵搞不清楚狀況
- Yes, what is it? - God, I'm with a heathen.
那是我的電話號碼本 那個是聖裘得
That is my callbox key. And that is Saint Jude.
聖裘得 他是注定失敗行動的守護神
Il Santo Jude. He's the patron saint of lost causes.
也是警員的
And policemen.
警員的守護神？
- Patron saint of policemen?
每個人都需要朋友
- Everybody needs a friend.
注定失敗的行動，警員…
Lost causes, policemen...
你想成為哪個？
- Which do you want to be?
我想成為一個警員 真的？
- I want to be a cop.- You do?
是的 為什麼？
- Yes. Why?
保護財產和市民…
'To protect the property and the citizenry...'
哦，嘿，那好吧
Whoa, it's all right.
什麼？
- What?!
我將授予你警員的職位 恭喜！
- I got to tell you, congratulations!
我可以為你和你的弟兄們拍張照片 嗎？
It's okay if I get a picture of you and your men?
好的，不過不會公開 只給我們看
Yeah. But not for publication. Just for us!
奈斯先生 你說了算
Anything you say, Mr Ness.
靠近點…噢，很好 好的，準備好了嗎？拿著
Closer in... Oh, that's great. Okay, ready? Hold it.
還要繼續過活呢
Life goes on.
一個人要變得卓越 他得有熱情
A man becomes preeminent, he's expected to have enthusiasms.
熱情…
Enthusiasms...
我的熱情是什麼？
What are mine?
什麼讓我讚賞？ 什麼給我快樂？
What draws my admiration? What is that which gives me joy?
女人！ 音樂！
- Dames! - Boozin'
歌劇！ 美酒！
棒球！
Baseball!
一個男人…
A man...
一個男人獨自站在場子中
A man stands alone at the plate.
該做什麼？
This is the time for what?
到了個人表現的時候
For individual achievement.
他獨自站在那裏
There he stands alone.
但在場上，是怎麼？
But in the field, what?
團隊的一部分
Part of a team.
合作、合作、合作
Teamwork...
看、投、捕、沖
Looks, throws, catches, hustles.
身為團隊的一部分
Part of one big team.
他自己打發一天，像 貝比魯斯和泰科布一樣
Bats himself the live-long day, Babe Ruth, Ty Cobb, and so on.
要是他的球隊不能上場， 他是什麼？
If his team don't field...what is he?
什麼都不是 什麼都不是
Nothing
你瞭解嗎？我想沒有人可以
You follow me? No one.
晴朗的天氣看台上的球迷爆滿 他得說些什麼呢？
Sunny day, the stands are full of fans. What does he have to say?
我要自己出去
I'm goin' out there for myself.
但是…我哪都去不了…
But...I get nowhere
…除非我的球隊贏了
unless the team wins.
團隊！團隊！
- Team! - Team.
上帝！
Jesus Christ!
現在我躺下休息了
'Now I lay me down to sleep'
祈禱上帝保佑我的靈魂
'I pray the Lord my soul to keep'
如果醒來前我死去了
'lf I should die before I wake'
祈禱上帝把我的靈魂帶走
'I pray the Lord my soul to take'
阿門！上帝保佑你
- Amen. - God bless...
上帝保佑媽媽，上帝保佑爸爸 上帝保佑玩具娃娃，阿門
God bless Mommy, God bless Annie, God bless Daddy. Amen.
阿門
Amen.
晚安 晚安
Good night.
晚安，爸爸 晚安，小女孩
- Good night, Daddy. - Good night, little girl.
想去惹惱愛斯基摩人嗎？小蝴蝶？
Want to rub Eskimo? Butterfly?
你想去哪兒？ 什麼？
- Where are you going? - What?
你想去哪兒？
Where are you going?
我想去樓下 明天有事兒要做
I thought I'd go downstairs, some work to do for tomorrow.
今天你工作了一整天，是嗎？ 是的，當然
- You had a full day today, though? - Yes, I certainly did.
你還有精力？ 噢，一大堆工作要做
And you've still got some energy left? Oh, a lot of work.
不過，你為什麼不上來幫我梳頭 我的偵探？
Well, why don't you come up and brush my hair? You 'Detective'
（十字軍警察分隊終於得分）
我們該怎麼做？
- How are we doin'
艾爾卡邦的組織狡詐 令人難以置信
- Capone's organisation is diverse.
看這個 它擁有加拿大控股公司協會
It owns Canadian Holding Company Associations, which owns in turn
該協會又擁有綠燈洗衣店
Green Light Laundry,
中西部計程車公司 歡樂時光玩具…
Midwest Cabs, Jolly Time Playthings...
歡樂時光玩具？ 是的，歡樂時光玩具？
- Jolly Time Playthings? - Yes.
提醒我給我女兒買一份禮物
Remind me to get a present for my daughter.
巴哈馬船運公司、露西小姐… 這清單沒完沒了！
...Bahama Ship-to-Shore, Miss Lucy Togs...the list is endless!
所有的生意都是合法的 並且它們都不屬於艾爾卡邦
And all the business is legitimate, and none is owned by Al Capone.
但是我們能以逃稅逮捕他 如果我們能查明
But we can get him on income tax evasion if we can show
那些組織業務的錢都流向他
that any of the 'organisation' business money is going to him.
從法律上來說，他沒有收入 他沒有獲得任何東西？
- Legally, he receives no income. - He doesn't receive anything?
打擾一下，奈斯先生 你有訪客
- Mr Ness? You have a visitor.
奈斯先生 我是奈斯
- Mister Ness!
我想知道我們能否談一會兒？
Could we talk for a minute?
43區市政議員約翰奧辛
I'm John O'Shea, Alderman...
是的，市政議員 我知道你是誰
Yes, I know who you are.
可以讓我們獨處嗎？
Would you excuse us?
我們手上有幾各大案子正在進行
We are busy with several large operations.
我們相當忙，市政議員 那麼，我能為您做些什麼呢？
What can I do for you?
我來祝賀你工作幹的漂亮
I came up to congratulate you on a job well done.
所以在如此美好的一天 特地來分享您的好運
Share your good fortune on such a lovely day.
這是什麼意思？
What's that?
什麼？ 先生，您是受過教育的人
- What is that? - Mr Ness, you're an educated man.
我們可以坦率地交談
Let me pay you the compliment of being blunt.
您正在破壞樁一大生意
There is a large and popular business which you are causing dismay.
為什麼您不能順應時勢 順其自然？
Why don't you just cross the street and let things take their course?
請進好嗎？
Would you come in here, please?
在羅馬時期
In Roman times,
當某人因試圖賄賂政府官員 而被定罪時
when a fellow tried to bribe a public official,
人們會割掉他的鼻子 並且將他和一個野獸
they would cut off his nose, sew him in a bag
縫在一個袋子裏 並把袋子扔進河裏
with a wild animal, and throw that bag in the river.
告訴你的負責人 我們不相為謀！
You tell your master that we must agree to...disagree!
你正在犯一個大錯誤
- You're making a mistake.
是嗎？我之前已經犯過錯誤 現在我正在享受
- I'm beginning to enjoy my mistakes.
你的同伴是鐵面無私的 有這回事嗎？
You fellows are 'untouchable' is that it?
沒人能說得動你？
No one can get to you?
你告訴卡邦… 嘿，每個人都能接近
You tell Capone...
…我將在地獄見他
that I'll see him in hell.
嘿！真漂亮的房子！我說 真漂亮的房子！你住在這兒？
Hey! Nice house! I said, nice house! Do you live there?
呵，小女孩要過生日了？
Little girl's havin' a birthday, huh?
是的 有一個家庭真不錯
Yes. Nice to have a family.
是的，的確是
Yes, it is.
一家之主可要當心 保證沒有什麼事會發生
A man should take care, see that nothin' happens to them.
凱瑟琳！
Catherine?!
Catherine!
孩子在哪兒？ 她在樓上，艾略特！
- Where's the baby? - She's upstairs. Eliot!
不
No
噢，你
Oh,you
你剛才在做什麼？ 我必須把衣服燙好
- What were you doing up? - I had to finish my ironing.
真的？
You did?
你現在跟爸爸來，好嗎？
You're gonna come with Daddy now, okay?
艾略特？好的，沒問題！
Eliot? Okay, it's all right!
好的，我們走
Okay, let's go.
站住！走在路上要當心
Stay there! Keep your eye on the street!
馬龍在哪兒？ 在監視，他馬上就到
- Where's Malone? - On the stake-out. He'll be here.
這小子是誰？
- Who's this guy?
他是名單上的一個人 沒事
- He's on Malone's list. He's okay.
那麼好吧 送他們到車站
Drive to the station.
當你去那兒時 她會告訴你往哪兒去
She'll let you know where to go when you get there.
是，長官 脫帽
Take off your hat.
如果有什麼事發生，先開槍 明白我的意思嗎？
Anything happens, shoot first. You understand me?
是的，奈斯先生
Yes, Mr Ness.
親親
Kiss.
愛斯基摩人和小蝴蝶，爸爸 好的
- Eskimo and butterfly, Dad. - Okay.
現在，出發！
Now, go!
馬龍！
Malone!
他們平安嗎？ 一切平安
- Are they okay? - Yeah.
你們確定那個警員很好嗎？ 嗯，他最好是，他是我的表兄弟
- You sure the cop's okay? - He'd better be, he's my cousin.
我想解決他，馬龍！ 你聽見我說的嗎？
I want to hurt the man, Malone! You hear me?!
我要開始和他周旋 我要解決卡邦
I want to take the battle to him. I want to hurt Capone.
那麼好吧，耶誕節快樂 因為我有些好消息告訴他
Well, then, a Merry Christmas, we've got some great news.
會有一個大型的國際運輸經過
A huge international shipment's coming.
我們知道時間、地點和整個情況
We've got the time, the place and the whole shebang.
好吧 那麼我們還站在這裏幹嘛？
Well, what are we doin' standin' here, then?
你怎麼得知這個消息的？ 這是警員工作的第二條規則
How do you come by this information? That's the second rule of police work:
如果你想保密 就不要告訴老闆
if you want to keep a secret, don't tell the boss.
你知道他每年賺 超過3百萬美金嗎？
You know he's making over $3 million a year?
但他從來不納稅 什麼都不在他名下
But he's paid no taxes, nothing's in his name.
要是我們能查清他的任何收入
If we can establish any payments to him,
我們就可以起訴他 逃避繳納所得稅
we can prosecute him for income tax evasion.
什麼？
What?
我說，我們可以起訴他 逃避繳納所得稅
I said, we can prosecute him for income tax evasion!
以稅務來治裁一個殺人犯？
Try a murderer for not paying his taxes?!
好吧，總比什麼都不做要好
Well, it's better than nothing.
好吧 那我們怎麼把他和錢聯繫上呢？
All right. How do we link him to the money?
我不知道
I don't know.
睡覺吧，奧斯卡
Go to sleep, Oscar.
一個5到10輛卡車的車隊 裝滿上好的加拿大威士忌
A convoy of 5-10 trucks with good Canadian whiskey
將會由卡邦組織 一個高層成員接頭
will be met by a high-level member of the Capone organisation.
他將以全額現金一次付清
He will be bringing full payment for the shipment in cash.
這交易將會就發生在美國的邊境內
Now, the meet is to take place just over the border on the American side.
我們的目標是要沒收現金和酒
We want to confiscate the liquor and the cash.
上尉？ 我們等著他們的信號
- Captain? - We will await their signal.
當他們在路上 並發出信號時
When they're on the road and have given the signal,
我們就從加拿大的橋邊衝出
we will engage from the Canadian side of the bridge.
然後從後方突襲他們
Thus taking them by surprise from the rear.
奈斯先生，你應當非常清楚 出其不意是成功的一半
And surprise, as you very well know, Mr Ness, is half the battle.
突襲是成功的一半 很多事情都是
Surprise is half the battle. Many things are half the battle.
失敗是成功的一半 讓我們想想什麼是全勝
Losing is half the battle. Let's think about what is all the battle.
讓我們出征，同胞們！ 謝謝你，上尉
Let's take the fight to them, gentlemen! Thank you, Captain.
好的！出發！
All right! Move out!
別緊張
Take it easy.
別緊張遲早會發生的
Take it easy! lt'll all happen in time.
這就是工作
This is the job.
別等著它發生 甚至不要想著它發生
Don't wait for it to happen, don't even want it to happen.
就看看發生了什麼
Just watch what does happen.
你是我的導師嗎？
Are you my 'tutor'?
是的，先生，我正是
Yes, sir, that I am.
你已經察看過？ 是的
- Did you check it already? - Yes, I did.
然後順其自然
Then leave it alone.
你是一個好警員，吉塞普
You're a good cop, Giuseppe.
你做得很好！你會做得正好
You're doing good. You're gonna do just fine.
華萊士，你冷嗎？ 是的，有一點
- Wallace, are you cold? - Yes, I am, a little.
跺跺你的腳，那樣會暖和些
Then stamp your feet. It'll keep you warm.
你有點經驗了 路遙知馬力
You learn something, 20 years walking the beat.
打小報告和站在雨中…
Stitches and standing in the rain...
聽著，奈斯先生…
Listen, Mr Ness...
我有一個主意
I had an idea.
你們都只有少量的子彈？
You all have your spare shells?
如果你們必須開火 拿低點並找出空間
If you have to fire, hold low and squeeze.
放倒他
And put your man down.
因為他將會同樣對待你 擊斃他
Because he'll do the same to you. Shoot to kill.
你聽見我說的話嗎？ 是的，擊斃他
- Did you hear what I said? - Yes, I did. Shoot to kill.
走吧
Let's go.
放鬆…
Easy...
那些加拿大人不會出現的 直到我晃動徽章
The Canadians will not show until I flash the badge.
所以我們必須穿過地面 迅速到達那座橋
So we must cover the ground to the bridge as quickly as possible.
喬治，看起來估計是正確的
George, the count's right.
我關心的不是計數 是酒桶的大小
I'm concerned about the size of these barrels!
馬龍，你和我將要…
Malone, you and I will take the men...
阻止那…
Stop it!
移開它！移開它 喬治！快點！
Move it! Move it, Georgie!
到那邊去！ 蓋住卡車！
Get over here!
丟掉那些東西！
Leave the stuff in the cars!
衝啊！
Charge!
什麼鬼東西！ 你最終會死於某種疾病
What the hell! You got to die of somethin'
看！他們來了！ 他媽的條子！我們走！
- Look! Here they come! - Mounties! Let's get out of here!
讓我們離開這兒！快！ 快離開！
Move, move!
走！
Let's go!
我簡直不敢相信！
I can't believe it!
這裏！這本賬簿！ 把它給我
- Here are the codes. - Give me that.
不要讓車離開橋！
Don't let those cars off the bridge!
掩護他！ 走！
Cove him!GAO
喬治史東，跑到車那兒去！
run to the car
史東，乘坐第一輛車！ 知道了！
Stone, take the first car!
把這東西扔一邊去
Get this shit out of the way!
我們走！ 走！快，開槍！
Let's  go,go!Fire!
硬漢！
Tough guy!
史東！
Stone!
走！
Go!
史東！
Stone!
我很好
I'm okay.
你們這些暴徒！
You thugs!
你還好嗎？
You all right?
是的，他在那兒 去把他弄過來！
Yeah. There he is! Go get him!
好的！真夠倒霉的！
All right! Enough of this running shit!
好了，喬治史東！ 我們得到了什麼？
Well, Georgie-boy! Well, what have we got here?
嗨
Hello.
好的！放下槍！
All right! Drop the gun!
舉起手來，你們被捕了
Put your hands in the air, you're under arrest.
我說，放下槍！
I said, drop it!
不許動！
Stop!
老天，難道你沒聽見我說的嗎？
God, didn't ya hear what I said?!
你們是聾子嗎？
What are you, deaf?!
這是什麼，鬧劇嗎？
What is this, a game?!
這裏，坐下
Here. Sit down.
好啦，史東會好的
Stone's gonna be all right.
我抓到帶著挎包的小子
I got the fellow with the satchel.
我要殺了他 噢，是的
- I had to kill him. - Oh, yeah.
他已經死了
He's as dead as Julius Caesar.
你想死嗎？ 不，我不想
- Would you rather it was you? - No, I would not.
好啦，你們已經盡責了 回家吧，今晚好好睡一覺
Well, then you've done your duty. Go home and sleep well tonight.
好吧，事情你都看見了 當你出外沒帶槍的後果
The things you see when you're out without your gun.
喂，史東 你從遙遠的南方來的吧
Now you're a long way from the Southside, George.
我在跟你說話
I'm talkin' to you.
你來這兒是為了開 一個射擊場嗎？
Did you come here to open a shooting gallery?
我要你寫出 你上司和聯繫人的名字
I want you to write down the names of your superiors and contacts.
你為什麼不供奉我的屁股 嘿！
Why don't you kiss my ass?
好的，你可能沒聽見我說什麼 艾略特奈斯？
- Perhaps you didn't hear me. - Eliot?
你朝聯邦警官開火 你們犯法了
- You've broken the law... - Eliot!
你會在Levanworth裏艱難地蹲上30 年
You can be tough in Leavenworth for 30 years.
你們將要成天待在裏面！ 那就是你們想要的嗎？
- You're going inside for all day! - Is that what you want?
艾略特奈斯！ 什麼？
- Eliot! - What?!
看！
Look at this!
看這個！ 這是什麼？
- Look at this! - What is this?
這是什麼？
What is this?
在這本賬簿裏 有很多金錢交易
You got a lot of money changing hands in this book.
這是什麼，「行政區」 和「警員管區」？
What is this, 'war'? And 'police precincts'
這裏有一個標題「巡迴法庭」
And you got a heading here... 'Circuit Court'
這裏有一個標題「巡迴法庭」 這是什麼？
You got a heading here, 'Circuit Court' What is this?
沒什麼 你們沒什麼可利用的
Nothin' There's nothin' you can make out of it.
如果我們能確定任何編碼 賬目是指給卡邦的付款
If any of these coded entries indicate payment to Capone,
那我們就可以處理卡邦了
then we can put Capone away.
我要你告訴我們 哪個賬目是艾爾卡邦的
- Which entry is Al Capone?
寇斯塔，是卡邦的代號嗎？
- A. Costa, is that his code name?
你要在監獄裏過一輩子 除非你和我們合作，老兄
You'll do the whole thing in the joint unless you help us.
我要你說明這個賬簿
Translate this ledger for us!
在地獄裏 在地獄？
- In hell. - In hell?!
你會搞砸一切，老兄 你會被吊死，除非你和我們合作
You will hang high unless you cooperate.
這個人可以指證艾爾卡邦 這個人能把艾爾卡邦送進監獄
This man can finger Al Capone, put him behind bars.
為什麼你們不他媽的滾蛋
Why don't you guys just fuck off?!
我沒有瞎干涉你 哈德凱斯先生！
I'm not fuckin' with you!
無論如何， 我們必須得到這些資訊
We'll have that information one way or another.
可不是那邊，出去 你可以說話了！
- Not that way. Out. - You're gonna talk!
你會求我們讓你說！ 總會有人說的！
You're gonna be beggin' to talk!
你狗娘養的 夠了你們，滾出去
- You dirty son-of-a-bitch! - Enough out of you.
嘿，你快來，走過來！
Hey, come on, you, on your feet!
我需要你幫我們說明這本賬簿
I need you to help me to translate this book!
我不會要求第二次
I'm not gonna ask you a second time.
我數到三
I'm gonna count to three.
怎麼？你嘴裏有把槍不能說話嗎？
What's the matter? Can't you talk with a gun in your mouth?
一
One.
二
Two!
三！
Three.
我說！
I'm gonna talk!
不要！你們想知道的一切事情 我都會一五一十的告訴你
Don't ! I'm gonna tell ya whatever ya want.
你們想要知道些什麼？
What do ya want to know?
在他講話之前 不要讓他替自己澄清
Now, don't let him clean himself until after he talks.
問問他你想知道事情
Now, ask him what you want to know.
好吧…
All right...
好，我要知道會計的名字
Okay, I want to know the name of the bookkeeper.
我要這些密碼的完整譯本
I want a complete translation of the code.
我要完整的資訊
I want a complete...
奈斯先生！
Mister Ness!
那麼，寇斯塔，是艾爾卡邦嗎？
是艾爾卡邦
我不贊同你的方法
I do not approve of your methods!
是嗎？那麼，你不是芝加哥人
Yeah? Well, you're not from Chicago.
什麼？ 他們的貨到手了
- What? - They got the shipment.
什麼？ 他們得到了所有的貨了
- What?! - They got the whole shipment.
我要那個狗娘養的給我馬上死！ 我們正試圖找到…
- I want that son-of-a-bitch dead! - We're trying to locate...
我是什麼，如此孤立無援？ 我有問過你想幹什麼嗎？
What am I, alone in this world? Did I ask you what you're tryin' to do?
不，艾爾卡邦，請不要這樣
No, Al Capone.
我要你找到這個雜種！
I want you to get this fuck where he breathes!
我要你找到那個叫 艾略特奈斯的娘娘腔
I want Eliot Ness dead!
我要他死！我要他全家死盡！
I want his family dead,
我要他的房子燒成平地！
his house burnt to the ground!
我要在半夜跑到那裏 在他的骨灰上撒尿！
I want to piss on his ashes!
看看這傢伙，這傢伙 他太可惡了
Look at this guy, this guy, he's so serious.
很好，他已經煩惱了好長時間 他？
- Well, he's got a lot on his mind. - He does?
是的 比如？
- Yes. - Like what?
比如說他的名字
Like what his name is.
「約翰福特」 我還認為一切都解決了
John, I thought that was all settled.
「約翰福特」，我覺得 我們喜歡「約翰福特」
I thought we liked John.
我猜想他的中間名字 應該是「羅」
I suppose his middle name will be Law.
不，是「愛德格」
No...it'll be Edgar.
應該是「傑愛德格」 我不這麼認為
- It'll be J. Edgar... - I don't think so.
老天，你真美麗
God, you're beautiful.
你昨晚就應該來看看我們的
You should have seen us last night.
我知道 我想過本來就應該到這裏的
I know. I should have been here. I wanted to be here.
我知道我明白，我懂
I know. I understand, I do.
告訴我，你一直都很小心嗎？ 比老鼠還要小心啊
Just tell me, are you being careful?
你有進展嗎？
- Careful as mice. - Are you making progress?
進展？ 有
- Progress? - Yes?
夫人，我覺得您的丈夫 已經找到了艾爾卡邦
Mrs Ness, I think your husband just became the man who got Al Capone.
先生們，有傳訊傳過來了
Gentlemen! A subpoena was issued for Alphonse Capone
是艾爾彭斯卡邦 今早在我辦公室旁邊
by my office this morning, for the crime of evading
是關於逃避或者密謀逃避 聯邦所得稅的罪行
and conspiring to evade Federal Income Tax.
卡邦的罪行能有多大？
- What's the maximum he could get? - If convicted on all counts,
如果所有的罪名成立 可以讓卡邦蹲28年的監獄
Mr Capone could have up to 28 years.
殺人犯？ 不好意思，我知道的就這麼多
Excuse me, that's all. Thank you.
好，現在出發 車在巷子裏
The car's in the yard.
當你把他帶到那裏時 不要接電話
When ya get him there, don't answer the phone.
我們將通知你，手機會響 兩次
- We'll call, let it ring... - Twice.
我們將在… 在角落
- We'll call... - From the corner.
誰要是敲門… 我明白，立刻斃了他
- Anybody knocks on the door... - Come out shooting.
你明白了？ 是的
I got it.
你非常喜歡執法的戰略方面 那是奧斯卡華萊士嗎？
You enjoy the tactical aspects of law enforcement, Oscar?
哦，是的它比賬本有趣多了
Much more diverting than accounting.
我們對你有好處 你對我們也有好處
I'm bein' good to you, you got to be good to me.
我們來達成一個協定 我們大家都遵守，可以麼？
We made a deal, we're gonna stick to it, okay?
恩，是，比作賬有趣多了
Oh, yes, much more diverting than accounting.
好，我們今晚和你碰面 是，好的
Okay, we see yous tonight.
很好，一路順風，永不止步
All right, all the way down and no stops.
…他能說，「我將毫無保留」
...he's been saying, "I will speak up."
在此我一定要讚揚 艾略特奈斯
For which I must commend the excellent work
和他的鐵面無私小組的 出色工作
of Eliot Ness and his squad of Untouchables.
是男孩或女孩？ 男孩
- What was it, a boy or a girl? - Boy.
男孩，恭喜！ 他叫什麼？
- Congratulations! What's his name?
約翰 約翰？
- John.- John? -
是的，約翰詹姆士
Yeah. John James.
那麼她還好嗎？ 恩，她還好
- So she's okay? - Yeah, she's okay.
實際上，當她離開時 她想重新粉刷整個房子
In fact, when she gets out, she wants to repaint the house.
當粉刷完了，她會發現房子 變得很小了，所以你得搬家
Then she'll find the house too small, you'll have to move.
完全正確
excatly
老天，結婚是一件美好的事 如果你能忍受這樣的痛苦
- Goodness, it's nice to be married. - If you can stand the pain.
伯恩斯先生，你知道 華萊士先生在哪裏嗎？
Mr Burns, where's Mr Wallace?
你難道沒有看到他嗎？ 他剛從服務電梯裏下去了
Didn't you see him? He just went down in the service elevator.
好的，很好
Well good
你能在任何時候眼觀八方… 放鬆點，一切都會好起來的
- You keep an eye out at all times... - Take it easy, we'll be fine.
他們要派人…
They are going to...
他說服務電梯嗎？ 是的
- Did he say the service elevator? - Yes.
華萊士！華萊士！ 我們從這裏走樓梯
- Wallace! Wallace! - Here, let's take the stairs.
（樓梯，消防水龍帶）
噢，不
Oh, no.
不，不！ 慢慢來…慢慢來！
- No, no! - Easy... Easy!
（正在載入）
奧斯卡華萊士
Oscar.
（可觸摸的）
噢，天啦
Oh, Jesus.
你還好吧？
You gonna be all right?
奈斯先生…
Mr Ness
當一個年輕的傢伙在這條 線路中壞事，這就是犯罪了
It's always a crime when a young guy goes down in the line, Jimmy.
我討厭看到它發生 在我認識的人身上
I'd hate to see it happen to someone I know.
有時最好不要介入
Sometimes it's better not to get involved.
吉米馬龍
Jimmy!
請一天假 暫時離開這個城市
Take a day off. Get out of the city for a while.
你明白我的意思嗎？
You know what I mean?
萊剋星頓酒店
艾爾卡邦 我們沒抓到卡邦先生啊…
- Al Capone. - We have no Mr Capone...
我知道，抓住他
- I know, get him.
我們沒有抓到卡邦先生啊… 我說，該死的…
- We have no Mr Capone...I said
我想說…
I said...
你想在這裏做什麼嗎？ 今天我朋友被殺了
- Something you want here? - My friend was killed today.
我不介意 你不在乎
- I don't care. - You don't care.
可是他現在已經這樣了
Now he does.
卡邦，出來 你想打架嗎？
Come on here, Capone. You want to fight?
你想打架 你和我，這裏？
You want to fight? You and me, right here?
就這樣，來吧！
That's it, come on!
你害怕從保鏢中走出來 為自己說話？
You afraid to come out from behind your men, to stand up for yourself?
你現在想這樣做嗎？ 你想要大幹一場嗎？
- You want to do the mat now?
來吧，你這個狗娘養的！
- Yeah! Come on, you son-of-a-bitch!
什麼？ 放輕鬆
- What? - Easy.
在我兒子面前 你竟敢這麼跟我說話？
You talk to me like that in front of my son?
操，操你全家！
Fuck you and your family!
放鬆點，是我！不是這邊 不是這邊
Easy. It's me. It's me! Not this way.
你操來操去，什麼都沒得到 你只會說大話
You fuck, you got nothin' You're nothin' but talk and a badge.
正因你沒得到，所以你在這 在法庭上你什麼都沒得到
You're here because you got nothin' in court,
你沒有抓到那個會計 你什麼都沒得到！
you got  no bookkeeper, nothin'
什麼都沒有！如果你還算個男人 你早就應該那樣做了！
If you were a man, you would've done it now!
一無所獲，你個廢物！
You got nothin' you punk!
好吧，不，我明白
Well, no, I understand.
相信我，我明白
Believe me, I understand.
好吧，發生什麼事了？
Well, what's happened?
他說他不能不受到保護
He says he can't be unprotected.
那個傢伙說了什麼？
What is it that the guy says?
他說 他不會讓自己做愚蠢的事情
He says he won't make a fool out of himself,
沒有證人他也不會出庭的
and he won't go into court without a witness.
所以明天早上 那個傢伙將會宣佈庭外和解
So tomorrow morning the D.A. will announce that he's dropping the case.
他將會放棄 我沒有那麼說
- He's gonna give up.
我說 沒有證人他也不會出庭的
- He won't do it without a witness.
我們有華來士的檔案和賬簿
We have Wallace's files and the ledgers.
有時候重新考量損失是必要的
There's a time when I think you have to cut your losses.
你好？
Hello?
你好
Hello.
是的
Yes.
不，他沒有成家
No, he didn't have a family.
一切進展怎麼樣？
How is everything there?
不，你只是做了你想要的
No, you do it however you want.
我承諾我會
I promise I will.
你把我的愛帶給她
You give her my love.
我也愛你
I love you, too.
奈斯先生，我們在這裏 發現了一本賬簿
Mr Ness, we got a ledger
上面記錄有向芝加哥 市政府官員付款
here listing payments to Chicago City officials.
找到卡邦和法蘭克尼提 我想我們今天有收穫了
- We got Al Capone, Frank Nitti... - I think that's enough for today.
但是如果我們不緊接著… 那樣行得通，史東先生，那樣可以
- If we don't stay on top... - That'll do. Thank you.
謝謝 我想請求留下來
I'd like to request to stick around.
我們該粉碎這些傢伙 我們必須
- We got to bust these guys. - I know we got to.
是這樣嗎？
Is that it?
什麼？ 你聽的沒錯
- I'm sorry? - You heard me.
我的問題是，我們結束了嗎？
My question is, are we done?
是的，我認為我們結束了
Yes, I think we're done.
你說我們現在正處於一場苦戰？
So we sat in at a game that was above our head?
似乎是這樣 對於華萊士先生也是這樣
It appears so. It appears so to Mr Wallace.
反正他死了 而且那個混蛋也準備和解
He's dead! And the D.A. is gonna drop the case!
該死的，沒有證人他不會出庭
He will not go into court without a witness
而且沒有卡邦的會計 沃爾特佩恩，他也不會出庭
and without Capone's bookkeeper, Walter Payne.
那你現在準備做什麼？ 你想讓我做什麼？
- What are you prepared to do now? - What would you have me do?
我已經盡可能地做了
I have taken this as far as it can go.
你老婆想要什麼？ 她想知道，如果我…
- What did your wife want? - She wanted to know if I was...
我老婆？ 是啊
- My wife? - Yeah.
她想知道我是否是對的
She wanted to know if I was all right.
結婚不錯吧，啊？
It's nice being married, eh?
是啊
Yes.
她正坐在某個房間 被一群陌生人包圍著
She's sitting in some room surrounded by people she doesn't know,
仔細檢查著… 廚房彩色圖片什麼的
going over... kitchen colour charts or something.
世界上的某些人依舊關心著 廚房的顏色是什麼
Some part of the world still cares what colour the kitchen is.
艾略特奈斯，我還想你為我 再做一件事
Eliot, I want you to do one more thing for me.
你回DA那裏去並且拖住他
Get back to the D.A. and stall him.
等等，拖住他？ 怎麼拖住他？
- Wait a minute, stall him with what?
照我說的做就行了
- Just do as I say.
我想我知道怎麼樣找到那個傢伙
I think I know how to find this guy.
（卡邦會計應訊）
沃爾特佩恩？
Walter?
艾爾卡邦說，在他解決傳訊之後 我們才能離開這座城市
Al says we got to get out of town until he can fix this subpoena thing.
我們今晚就出發
We're leavin' tonight.
兩球入袋
Two ball, down.
麥克，你有時間嗎？ 嗯，我現在有，不是嗎？
Mike, you got a minute? I do now, don't I?
吉姆馬龍，你現在 在警員隊伍裏做什麼？
And what are you doin' in a club for cops, Jimmy?
這是警員的地方 我們能夠借一步說話嗎？
This is a place for cops. Can we step outside?
可以，可以，當然可以 但我沒有什麼要對你說的
All right, all right, but I got nothin' to say to ya.
我們到底要去哪裏 游泳嗎？
Where the hell are we going, for a swim?
傻瓜，不要淋雨啊
Get out of the rain, you fool.
什麼？什麼？
What? What?!
我只是需要再一個資訊
I just need one more piece of information.
再一個？吉姆馬龍！
One more? Jimmy!
我只為了你冒生命危險 我需要找到那個會計
- I just risked my life for ya. - I need to find that bookkeeper.
你瘋了嗎？你是瘋了
Are you crazy? Y ou're crazy.
我警告過你必須 得離開這個城市
I warned you to get out of town.
若他們知道是我，我死定了 我需要找到那個會計
- If they knew it was me, I'm dead. - I need to find that bookkeeper.
你他媽的胡說八道，老兄！ 你真他媽的瘋了！
You're fuckin' nuts, man! You're out of your fuckin' mind!
你真的瘋了！ 我救過你的命
And I tried to save your life.
放開你的手
Get your hands off.
你欠我的，吉姆.馬龍 我不欠你任何東西
You owe me, Jimmy, I don't owe you nothin'
我的人都被殺了 你的人？我們才是你的人啊！
- My people are being killed. - We're your people!
你們是我的人？ 是啊
You?!
你他媽的和外人一起混啊！ 麥克，他們已經毀了這個城市
You fuckin' run with the dagos! They've ruined this town.
十年來我因這些事吃不下飯 不斷告訴自己我是一個警員
For ten years I can't say that I'm a cop for the shit that's goin' on!
啊，廢話！真他媽的廢話！ 看看你自己！看看你自己！
Ah, bullshit! Fuckin' bullshit! Look at yourself! Look at yourself!
帶上你舒適的衣服和聯邦 傀儡生活在你的遊戲里
Go on and live the charade, with your soft clothes and federal stooges.
你認為他到底要做什麼？
- What do you think he's gonna do?
閉上你的嘴！ 他要剷平這座城市嗎？
- Keep your mouth off that!
我要知道這個傢伙在哪裏 而且我現在必須馬上知道！
I need to know where this guy is, and I need to know now!
我要把你從你生命中 做過的那些蠢事中帶出來！
I'm gonna rat you out for all the shit that I know that you've done!
我將改變你的心意！
I'm gonna turn you over!
吉姆馬龍 這是死人和我在說話
- This is a dead man talkin' to me.
是嗎？
- Is it?
你死了
You're dead.
你認為你自己算老幾啊？
Who the hell do ya think ya are?
早上我要把你的屁股 掛在旗桿上
I'll have your ass hangin' from the flagpole in the mornin'
我們中斷這個話題吧，老兄
Let's cut the woofing, pal.
你要告訴我
You tell me,
否則醫院和 太平間正等著你！
or you're going to hospital or the fuckin' morgue!
老天 你一定要幫助我達成任務
You're gonna fight it out and we'll have a case.
什麼？憑什麼？我不會 陷入困境或愚弄…
Yes? On what basis? I'm not gonna make a fool...
先生，不要告訴我 你要自作愚蠢
Don't tell me about makin' a fool out of yourself.
我已經安排了一些人在那裏 他們冒的風險比那個大多了
I have men out there risking more than that.
而且我被告知 那兒有一個帶路的
We have a lead, and we are following that lead
我們冒險跟著這個引導 危險大多了
at risk to more than our standing.
所以你現在還敢停止嗎
So don't you dare stop now.
是的，史東 我要奈斯
- Yeah, Stone. - Give me Ness.
他不在這裏，他在那個DA那裏 發生什麼事情？
He's at the D.A. 's.
告訴他我知道佩恩在哪裏 並馬上來我住的地方找我
Tell him I know where Payne is and to meet me at my place.
阿爾.卡邦！阿爾.卡邦！ 卡邦先生！
- Al! Al! - Mr Capone!
怎麼樣了… 那個案子怎麼樣了？
- What about that court case?
我會告訴你一些情況
- I'm gonna tell ya somethin'
有人整我 我也要整他
Somebody messes with me, I'm gonna mess with him.
有些人向我行竊 我就說，「你偷東西」
Somebody steals from me, I'm gonna say 'you stole'
和他講話 可不是因為在人行道上吐痰
not talk to him for spittin' on the sidewalk.
你明白了嗎？
You understand?
現在我沒有做任何事情 傷害這些人
Now, I have done nothing to hurt these people.
但是他們都很生我的氣 所以，他們做了些什麼？
But they're angered at me. So what do they do?
醫生沒有病患，所以過來繳收入稅…
Doctor up some income tax, for which they got no case,
來煩我
to annoy me.
像正常人那樣和我講話？不
To speak to me like men? No.
去騷擾一個安靜的人
To harass a peaceful man.
如果我曾經是個罪人 我請求上帝原諒我
I pray to God that if I ever have a grievance,
我只是想要 更多的一點自尊
I would have just a little more self respect.
卡邦先生！卡邦先生！ 只是還有一個問題！
Mr Capone!Mr Capone!
我想還告訴你一件事情
I'll tell you one more thing.
你竭盡全力參加職業拳擊賽 並且等到比賽結束
In an all-out prize fight,
一個人還站在那裏 那樣你就知道誰贏了
when one guy's left standing, that's how you know who won.
（拉辛路1634號）
這難道不像美國的那些黑人嗎？
Isn't that just like a wop?
在槍戰上帶刀
Brings a knife to a gun fight.
滾開，你這個混蛋外國佬！
Get out of here, ya dago bastard!
閃開，滾
Go on, get your ass out of here!
槍聲！槍聲！ 那裏有槍擊案！
Shots! Shots! I heard shots!
後退 都給我馬上後退
Stay back, everybody stay back, right now.
後退啊
Round the back.
馬龍！
Malone!
Malone.
該死的！史東！
Goddamn! Stone!
史東！
Stone!
電話！
The phone!
哦，我的天啦  快叫救護車！
Oh, God. Call an ambulance!
我是財務部的史東 拉辛大街，我需要救護車
This is Stone, Treasury Department, 1634 Racine, we need an ambulance.
什麼？ 拉辛街！
- What? - 1634 Racine!
這個？ 你要這個？
This? You want this?
你要這個？
You want this?
什麼？
What?
會計 什麼？
- Bookkeeper. - What?
會… 會計？
- Book... - The bookkeeper?
會計 會計？什麼？
- Bookkeeper! - The bookkeeper? What?
會計，他現在在火車上？ 是的
- The bookkeeper, he's on this train? - Yes.
他在火車上
He's on this train.
現在！你準備幹什麼？
Now! What are you prepared to do?!
不！馬龍！不
No. Malone. No.
站住站住
Stay. Stay.
站住！
Stay! Malone...
不不，不！
No. No, no!
不是這個人…不是這個人…
Not this... Not this man...
奈斯先生 火車12：05要開往邁阿密
Train's leavin' for Miami 12.05, Mr Ness.
我們會在那裏
We'll be there.
會計死了對我們沒有任何好處
The bookkeeper's no good to us dead.
史東？ 是的，長官
- Stone? - Yes, sir.
（往所有的方向）
包圍南入口
Cover the south entrance.
我們快到家了 我們快到家了
We're almost home. We're almost home.
請注意
Your attention, please.
通往邁阿密的快車 在第33月台於12:05開車
The Miami Flier departs at 12.05 from 33.
所有的乘客請全部上車
All aboard.
待在那裏，待在那裏
Stay right there. Stay right there.
待在那裏 親愛的，待在那裏
Stay right there. Stay right there,
哦，天使
honey.
旅客們請注意 開往邁阿密的列車於12：05啟程
Your attention, please. The Miami Flier, leaving at 12.05,
現在請在第33月台上車 請全部上車！
now boarding on track 33. All aboard!
耶 剛剛好 剛剛好 你待在那裏
Just here.
我知道我們快到家了
I'm just gonna leave this right here.
旅客朋友們請注意？
Your attention, please.
開往邁阿密的列車將於12:05開車 現在請在第33月台上車
The Miami Flier, leaving at 12.05,
請全部上車！
is now boarding on track 33. All aboard!
還有一個，我們上車吧
One more. Here we go.
好的，我們上車 你們準備好了嗎？
Here we go. You ready?
親愛的，我已經在這裏了 我們出發吧
I'm right here, honey. Here we go.
旅客朋友們請注意 旅客朋友們，注意
Your attention, please. May I have your attention, please?
這是關於通往邁阿密 快車的最後通知
This is the final call for the Miami Flier,
12:05在第33月台開車 請全部乘客上車！
leaving at 12.05 on track 33. All aboard!
現在，讓我幫忙提你的行李 哦，非常感謝
- Here, let me. Get your bags. - Oh, thank you so much.
先生，謝謝你
Thank you.Sir
你還好嗎？謝謝你
Are you all right? Thank you.
你真是一個紳士 非常感謝你的幫助
You're such a gentleman. It's so kind of you to help me.
我實在不敢確定 我們是不是做到了
I really wasn't sure if we'd make it or not.
我能幫你 處理些什麼事情嗎？
Is there some problem I can help you with?
沒有 我確實是很感謝你
- No. - I really can't thank you enough.
難道不有趣嗎？甜心 你真是個好孩子
Isn't this fun? You're being such a good boy, sweetheart.
再次感謝！
Thank you again, this is so wonderful.
先生，謝謝你
Thank you, sir.
請讓我帶他離開這裏 你已經幫了很多了
Please, let me take it from here. You've been such a great help.
非常感謝
Thank you so much. We're almost there.
先生，我將從這裏帶走 非常感謝您的幫忙
I'll take it from here, sir. Thank you very much for your help.
謝謝你，先生
Thank you.Sir
別哭了，甜心 我們快回到家了
Don't cry, sweetheart. We're almost home.
出了什麼事嗎？
Is something wrong?
先生？
Sir?
快點！ 離開這裏
Come on! Come on, let's get out of here.
你幹什麼？ 閉嘴！我說了，閉嘴！
- What are you doin' - Shut up!
你在幹什麼？ 你他媽閉嘴！
- What are you doin' - Shut the fuck up!
拿著它！
- Hold it!
拜託… 拿著它
- Please...Hold it!
我的寶寶！ 待在這兒，他沒事
- My baby! - Stay there. He's all right.
閉嘴！我說了拿著它！
I said hold it!
我要和會計一起出去走走
I'm walkin' out with the bookkeeper.
我們開車走
The bookkeeper and me are drivin' away.
明白沒？要不他死 他死了，你們什麼都得不到
See? Or else he dies. He dies, and you ain't got nothin'
給你們五秒鐘決定
You got five seconds to make up your mind.
我說
- I'll tell ya
我告訴你們所想知道的一切！ 閉嘴！我不是說著玩！
- I'll tell ya what ya want to know! - Shut up! I'm not kiddin'
他瘋了！你不必這樣做 我告訴你們所想知道的一切！
He's crazy! Don't let him do this, I'll tell you what you want to know!
你瞄準他了？ 是的，我瞄準了
- You got him? - Yeah, I got him.
一！ 不要
- One! - Will you stop it!
解決他
Take him.
二
Two.
這帳簿上的兩個編碼賬目 代表現金支出
The two coded entries in this ledger
是給各級政府官員 警員人員
represent cash disbursement to all levels of city officials,
還有艾爾彭斯卡邦
members of the police and to Alphonse Capone.
沒錯 你說什麼？
- That's correct. - Excuse me?
我說沒錯
I said that is correct.
你會替我們解釋這些 編碼賬目？
And you will decipher these coded entries for us?
是的
I will.
對不起，佩恩先生，我聽不到 是的，我會
Sorry, Mr Payne, I can't hear you. I said, I will.
你負責替卡邦先生 開支費用？
You were in charge of disbursements for Mr Capone?
是的
Yes, I was.
你親自將那些
And you personally distributed monies...
未報稅的巨款
..vast, undeclared monies...
交給卡邦先生？
..to Mr Capone?
是的
Yes, I did.
你能告訴我總數嗎？
Would you tell us the amounts?
三年來
In a three-year
我親自交給卡邦先生
period I personally disbursed monies to Mr Capone
一百三十多萬元
in excess of one and a third million dollars.
請你再重複一次？
Would you repeat that amount, please?
一百三十多萬元
- One and a third million dollars.
非常感謝
- Thank you very much.
我不明白 卡邦為何有持無恐？
I don't understand it. What does Capone have?
我們把他逼到絕路 而他卻一直在微笑
We're nailing the lid on his coffin, and he's smiling.
那狗娘養的在法庭上帶了槍
The son-of-a-bitch is wearing a gun in court.
叫法警來
Get me the bailiff.
很快會結束的
It'll be a fast trial.
前排穿白西裝的人 身上帶了把槍
The man in the front row wearing a white suit is carrying a gun.
我不想出什麼事 所以你抓他時
I don't want this to turn into something.
我會帶你出去 是的，長官
I'll lead you out.
能和你談會兒嗎？
Could we speak to you a minute, please?
面對牆壁 你到底是誰？
- Get up against it.
你聽到他的話了！ 面對牆壁！
- You heard him. Now, up against it!
這是幹嘛？
- What's this?
好了，把口袋掏空 放桌子上，全拿出來
- Empty all your pockets, all of it.
我有帶槍的許可 我看看
- I've got a permit for that. - Fine, let's see it.
遭起訴的人不是我
- I'm not the one under indictment.
把東西放在桌上
- Everything on the table.
給我看看 把槍還他
- Let me see. - Give him his gun back.
「相關人員看到此信 請通融一下」
"To Whom It May Concern. Please extend to the bearer,"
「請給予持有人法蘭克尼提先生 一切的方便」
"Mr Frank Nitti, all possible courtesy and consideration."
「威廉湯姆 芝加哥市長」
"William Thompson, Mayor of the City of Chicago."
對不起，奈斯先生 你必須把槍還給他
I'm sorry, Mr Ness, you'll have to give it back.
好吧
Fine.
但那傢伙不准再進入法庭 你明白嗎？
But that man does not go back into that courtroom. Do you understand me?
是的，長官
- Yes, sir.
（拉辛路1634號）
1634 Racine...
你知道嗎 我曾有位朋友住在那裏？
You know, I used to have a friend who lived there.
不要讓他走
Don't . Let him go.
不要！ 槍給你
- No! - Here, take it.
我在這兒呢，財政官員 來呀，逮捕我啊！
Here I am, Treasury Man. Come on! Harass me!
你在等什麼？
What are you waitin' for?
別光站在那裏！逮捕我呀！
Don't just stand there! Harass me!
別惹火我
Don't push me.
他們會燒死你的，老兄 是嗎？
- They're gonna burn you, buddy. - Yeah?
沒錯，我要看你被燒死 狗娘養的！
Yeah. I'm gonna come see you burn, you son-of-a-bitch!
因為你殺了我的朋友！
'Cause you killed my friend!
他死得像隻豬一樣 你說什麼？
- He died like a pig. - What did you say?
我說你朋友死前 哀號得像豬一樣
I said that your friend died screaming like a stuck Irish pig.
等我脫罪時，你慢慢想吧
Now you think about that when I beat the rap.
他聽起來是那樣嗎？
Did he sound anything like that?
拍張照，拍張照
One picture, come on, one picture.
奈斯先生，看看這個
Mr Ness, take a look at this.
奈斯先生？
Mr Ness?
奈斯先生，你還好嗎？ 你最好看看這個
Mr Ness, are you doin' okay? I think you'd better see this.
這是什麼？ 這是什麼？這是陪審團名單
- What is it? - That's the jury list, Mr Ness.
他們被收買了
They've been bribed.
從尼提的衣服裏搜出來的
I got it out of Nitti's coat.
尼提呢？
Where is Nitti?
他在車上
He's in the car.
這構不成證據 沒有出處
This constitutes no evidence
我可不允許… 庭上，事實是
. I'm not about to allow...Your Honour, the truth is
卡邦是個殺人兇手 並且將他無罪釋放
that Capone is a killer and he will go free.
對付他這種人只有一種辦法 那就是追捕他直至抓獲
There is only one way to deal with such men, and that is hunt them down.
這樣做了我違背了我的誓言
I have. I have forsworn myself.
我違背了我誓言 要維護的一切法律
I have broken laws I swore to defend.
我成了我想成的人 我很滿意我做的事
I am content that I have done right.
必須阻止那個人你必須…
That man must be stopped, you must...
我將判斷我必須做的事 奈斯先生
I'll be the judge of what I must do, Mr Ness.
請允許我們離開
Would you excuse us?
法警 是，長官
- Bailiff. - Yes, sir.
法警 我要你去隔壁霍夫曼的法庭
I want you to go next door to Judge Hoffman's Court,
他們剛開始聽證離婚案
where they've just begun hearing a divorce action.
我要你把那兒陪審團帶來 把這裏的陪審團帶過去
I want you to bring that jury in here and take this jury to his court.
法警，你聽清楚了嗎 是的，長官，我明白
- Are those instructions clear? - Yes, sir, they're clear.
他說什麼？這在幹嘛？
What's he talking about?
我要你調換陪審團
Bailiff, I want you to switch the juries.
是的，長官 庭上，我反對！
Your Honour, I object!
駁回
Overruled.
你跟他說什麼了？
What did you tell him?
我說他的名字也在帳簿上
I told him his name was in the ledger, too.
但他的名字並不在帳簿上
His name wasn't in the ledger!
等等這就是法律？ 那兒怎麼了？
Wait a second! Is this the law? What's goin' on here?
你不守規矩 那兒怎麼了？
- You're out of order. - What's goin' on?
我認為我們必須… 我不在乎做點什麼
- I think... - Do somethin' here.
你怎麼看我？ 做點什麼做點什麼！
What do I look like to you? Do somethin'
肅靜！
Order!
庭上，我們撤回無罪申辯…
Your Honour, we'd like to withdraw our plea of Not Guilty,
…改為有罪申辯
and enter a plea of Guilty.
有罪？ 法庭上肅靜！
- Guilty? - Order in the court!
肅靜！
Order!
有罪！
Guilty
法警！我說，肅靜！ 庭上！
Bailiff! Bailiff!
法警，肅清法庭！ 庭上！
Bailiff, clear the courtroom!
我這兒需要控制一下！ 艾略特奈斯
Eliot!
庭上！ 庭上，這公正嗎？
Your Honour! Is that justice?
他為什麼要調換陪審團？
Please, why did he switch the jury?
你現在要幹嘛？ 繼續跟著組織？
Are you gonna go after the organisation?
抱歉
Excuse me.
請問庭上，這公正嗎？
I'm askin' Your Honour, is this justice?
正義何在？
What justice ?
庭上！這樣公正嗎？
Is this justice?
等等，等等，等等！
Wait,Wait,Wait,Wait,
等等！
Wait,
絕不停止，絕不停止戰鬥 直到戰鬥終止
Never stop fighting till the fight is done.
他說什麼？你在說什麼？
What did you say?
我說絕不停止戰鬥 直到戰鬥終止
I said, never stop fighting till the fight is done.
什麼？ 你聽到了，卡邦，都結束了
- What? - You heard me, Capone. It's over.
滾開，你只會說大話
You're nothin' but a lot of talk and a badge.
最後一課 你只知道口出狂言
Here endeth the lesson.
你只知道口出狂言！
You're nothin' but a lot of talk and a badge!
「鐵面無私 打擊罪犯」
「奈斯保證不被收買」
「卡邦今天出庭」
「卡邦被判十一年徒刑 今天開始執行」
太多暴力了
So much violence.
總算清理了一點
Cleaning up a little.
我想該說再見了
I guess this is goodbye.
再見，喬治史東
Goodbye, George.
我要…為此感謝你
I want to...thank you for this.
不，謝謝你
No. Thank you.
奈斯先生，我認為他希望 你能保有它
Mr Ness... I think he would have wanted you to have that.
不，他希望送給警員
He'd have wanted a cop to have it.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
奈斯先生！ 你對這標題有何意見？
Mr Ness! Any comment for the record?
「當場捉拿卡邦的人」
'The man who put Al Capone on the spot.'
我只是適逢其時而已
I just happened to be there when the wheel went round.
聽說禁酒令將取消
They say they're going to repeal prohibition.
你會怎麼做？
- What will you do then?
也許我會去喝上一杯
- I think I'll have a drink.